Full Stack Software Engineer

Summary

9 years of full stack development experience
Leadership and mentoring experience
Based in London, UK
Available immediately

Tech Stack

Angular, TypeScript

.Net, C#

SQL Server

Azure

Contact

adam.horvath.0827@gmail.com

adamhorvath.dev | adam.horvath.0827@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adamhvt | medium.com/@adamhvt

Profile

Experienced Full Stack Software Engineer with 9 years of experience working with **Angular** and **.NET**, and experience leading small teams and building frameworks. Looking to obtain the position of Senior Software Engineer in a fast-paced tech environment to further improve professionally and utilise well honed skills in designing and implementing solutions for the web. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

Work experience

Phinsys Ltd (London, Insurtech)

2022 - Senior Software Engineer

Technologies: Angular 14+, Nx, .Net 7+, SQL Server, Azure

Worked on the next generation of the company's flagship data modelling and data processing product used for building data warehouses, reporting and providing data for external financial systems. I was responsible for delivering key system components:

- <u>Data modelling module:</u> Key part in building a module that allows browsing, building and combining different data sources that are fed into ETL processes.
- ETL process builder: Built a diagramming user interface similar to Azure Data Factory and AWS Glue for drawing processes, and the backing system components for managing process models and process configurations.
- <u>Full-stack application framework</u>: Actively contributed to the framework used to bolster building the flagship and other future products. Built several general purpose UI controls and controls used for data modelling. Also built smaller developer tools, e.g. data model comparer, ESLint rules.

This is Motif Ltd (London, Market Research)

2020-2022 Software Engineer

2022-2022 Development Manager

Technologies: Angular 10+, .Net Core, SQL Server, Cosmos DB, MongoDB, Azure Storage, Azure Functions

Instrumental role in designing and implementing software solutions for delivering and presenting market research data. Responsibilities included designing and implementing features and modules for multiple client facing reporting and content management systems and an internal project management system. In 2022 I became responsible for managing software development within the company.

Highlighted responsibilities and achievements:

- Lead developer of the flagship content management and reporting system: I was responsible for managing feature and change requests for the flagship content management system.
 Thechnologies used: Angular 10-14, .Net 6, SQL Server, Cosmos DB, DevOps and Azure.
- <u>Lead developer of a sample processing workflow system:</u> I was responsible for implementing optimisations and new features for a system which is used for processing survey sample files with high throughput using Azure Functions.
 - Technologies used: Angular 10-14, .Net 6, Azure Functions, SQL Server, Cosmos DB, DevOps and Azure.
- <u>Full software redesign of an internal project management system</u>: Managed to improve code quality, maintainability and extensibility by a large margin. The project resulted in significant performance and UX improvements, highly improving the efficiency of project management.
 - Technologies used: Angular 14, .Net6, SQL Server, MongoDB.

adamhorvath.dev | adam.horvath.0827@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adamhvt | medium.com/@adamhvt

L&M Solutions Consulting (Budapest, Consulting)

2015-2017 Part-time Software Engineer

2017-2019 Software Engineer and Lead Engineer

Technologies: Angular, React, Net Framework, SharePoint, SQL Server

Worked on several enterprise web solutions as a full-stack engineer, later as forward deployed engineer and team lead. I was involved in the whole software delivery lifecycle, including requirement analysis, system design, hands on coding, managing development and project progress, presenting results to stakeholders, documentation and deploying solutions.

Clients included a major Hungarian bank, a German automotive company, Central European oil and gas supply companies among others.

Highlighted projects:

- <u>Lead developer for an Automotive manufacturing support system:</u> Architected and led the development of an automotive manufacturing quality test management system with complex user interfaces and workflows for one of the major automotive brands. Worked productively with clients to understand requirements and user needs, was able to keep balance between speed of delivery and quality, while meeting high quality and security standards.
 - Technologies used: Angular 4+, .Net Framework, SQL Server
- <u>Intranet portal for one of the largest banks in Central Europe</u>: Developed several software components for creating, targeting and consuming news articles, recommendations and social network features using SharePoint's SPFx framework and React with TypeScript.
 - Technologies used: React 15+, SharePoint, SPFx
- <u>Full-stack application framework to bolster delivering projects on a fast pace</u>: Key contributions to the frontend half of an in-house full-stack framework used to support building web applications. This framework has been used for delivering numerous projects of small to large scale.

Technologies used: AngularJS-Angular 4+, .Net Framework, SharePoint, SQL Server

Skills

Technical skills

- Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS, Sass
- .Net, .Net Core, C#
- SQL Server
- Azure, DevOps
- Agile Development, Web Application Design and Architecture, Responsive and Adaptive UI Design
- Also familiar with React, SharePoint, MongoDB, CosmosDB

Soft skills

- Commitment to delivering value
- · Ability to handle multiple workstreams and prioritize accordingly
- Active learner, maintaining a technical blog
- Team-oriented: Making the most out of collaboration, can give constructive, beneficial feedback
- Ability to communicate engineering concepts to technical and non-technical stakeholders
- Enjoying mentoring and teaching other developers

adamhorvath.dev | adam.horvath.0827@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adamhvt | medium.com/@adamhvt

Education

Óbuda University, Budapest

Bachelor of Science in Engineering Information Technologist (2017)

Interests

Software Design and Architecture, Software Security, UX, Science